Kamil Oczkowski

GitHub github.com/oczkowski
Portfolio oczkow.ski

Email contact@oczk.io

Personal summary

I'm a determined and passionate individual. I really enjoy learning new technologies/programming languages as well as applying this knowledge to new or existing projects. My main programming language is JavaScript in which I have 3 years of commercial and 6 years of personal use experience.

Experience

Maglabs Ltd - React Developer

January 2021 - Present

- Developing and fixing the existing React Application using TypeScript
- Creating reusable components and solutions for data fetching using an in-house object storage API and dedicated product API
- Integrating QuickSight reporting into the React Application
- Planning, estimating and prototyping a rewrite of the existing React code with Redux Saga, TypeScript, Jest and Enzyme using pure components and dedicated API Class.

Smarter Click Technology Ltd - Mid-Level Web Developer

February 2019 - December 2020

- Writing future proof and understandable JavaScript code for the admin dashboard, refactoring existing code based to be more robust and ready for future upgrades.
- Working with AWS including DynamoDB, S3, and CodeCommit to automate the deployment of existing applications. Integrating these services with Node and aws-sdk.
- Helping on the React client dashboard and building new components.
- Working on existing PHP code with back-end developers.
- Lead support front-end developer on a small customer facing team.
- Leading a React/Redux client dashboard project.

Projects

Get Me a Bus - github.com/oczkowski/GetMeABus

Node / Express.js application for checking the TFL bus arrivals. The application is very basic but much quicker than any other web based application. When entering the page you're 3 clicks away from seeing you bus arrivals.

LED Control Dashboard - github.com/oczkowski/LEDControlDashboard

This application consists of 3 repositories, a C++ ESP8266 software for controlling LED strips using FastLED Library with a custom LED type, Node.js API engine with Redis implementation and a front-end React application with Redux linked up to WebSockets using socket.io.

Stack

- JavaScript (Newest ECMAScript Standards)
- Node.is (NPM)
- webpack / Babel
- Unix / Git
- AWS (S3, DynamoDB, Amplify, CodePipeline CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, EC2)
- React / Redux
- TypeScript
- C++ (Basic)
- MongoDB
- Node.js, aws-sdk
- Docker (Basic)

Education

IT Level 3 BTEC (Programming) 2013 – 2014 | 2015 – 2016

Havering College of Further and Higher Education | Hornchurch, Essex Object oriented programming, Event driven programming, Procedural Programming, Website hosting, Designing Object Oriented Application (C#), Legal implication of copyright, Networking

I hereby consent to the processing of the personal data for recruitment purposes.		